Master,
Red Scene
Animation Number "None"
お前様よ 実は折り入って相談したいことがあるのじゃが
I have something important to discuss with you.
どうじゃ ここはひとつ腹を割って話さんか
Well?
Do you have a moment to talk?
How about later?
後じゃ駄目なのか 勉強ひと段落するまで待てねーのかよ
Can't it wait until I'm done studying?
It's actually a rather serious situation.
それが結構深刻な話なのじゃ
One that requires drastic action.
ことは急を要する
What is it?
なんだよ
All right...
分かったよ 聞いてやるよ
I'll listen.
Master,
お前様よ 儂が極秘ルートから入手した情報によると
according to secret information I've acquired,
Mister Donut is having
ミスタードーナツが
今全品百円セールを行っておるらしいのじゃ
a sale where where each donut costs only 100 yen!
If we don't leave immediately, they'll sell out...
これは 今すぐ行かんと売り切れてしまうぞ
あ...分かった分かった
Fine, fine.
夕食前に気分転換がてら買いに行ってきてやるよ
I'll go buy you some before dinner,
so I can get out of the house.
You like golden chocolate, right?
ゴールデンチョコレートが好きなんだったよな
いや
No.
Take me there.
儂を店まで連れて行くがよい この目で見て選びたいのじゃ
I want to choose them myself!
It's really sunny out.
日光すごいけど 外に出られるのか
Will you be okay?
ま ちょっと日に焼ける程度じゃ
I'll just get a nasty sunburn.
儂も今や まっとうな吸血鬼とは言えんからのう
I'm not really a normal vampire anymore.
日焼け止めクリームとは言わんまでも
I won't even need sunscreen.
帽子でもかぶれば大丈夫じゃろう
Just a hat should suffice.
No, I'll let you know when we're at the store.
じゃ 店の前に着いたら合図するから
Until then, stay in my shadow.
せめてそれまでは陰に潜んでろよ
You'd prefer to minimize your time in the sun, right?
お前も日光に当る時間は少しでも少ない方がいいんだろう
Yes. The sun is my enemy.
うん 太陽は儂の敵じゃ
It'll only take thirty minutes or so.
三十分もすればつくからさ 頑張って起きてろ
Be sure to stay awake.
では後程 じゃあ
See you soon, then.
Bye.
"Hm," said Tsukihi, as she nodded her head with an unsure expression.
She also appeared lighthearted and relaxed with her head slightly tilted back.
Droopy eyes; loose expression.
Slumped shoulders; slouched back.
It's as if she's a lounging panda.
But I can't let myself be deceived by her appearance.
It's quite obvious that she's nowhere near lighthearted or relaxed,
since just this morning, she practically beat Karen and me to a pulp.
She isn't the slightest bit sleepy. She's a fully alert panda, a bear.
In my honest opinion, of the two fire sisters, Karen would be much easier to control, since she's a reckless idiot.
But Tsukihi is an uncontainable fool, one that goes beyond capable manipulation.
She has her hysterical peaks.
If Karen is the red flame, then Tsukihi would be the blue flame.
Being careless means getting burnt.
Not just a slight singe of the skin, but a deep scorching to the bone.
Tsukihi Phoenix Part 3
Episode 10
Type Font Used HGP Minchou B
お兄ちゃん またお出掛け
Onii-chan?
Heading out again?
Yeah... I am.
おう またお出掛け
Onii-chan, will Karen-chan be back late again today?
お兄ちゃん 火憐ちゃん今日は遅くなるのかな
さあ わかんね
I dunno.
ふうん そっか
I see.
まあ火憐ちゃんも熱くなると 前が見えなくなっちゃうタイプだからねえ
Well, when she's really into something,
she stops paying attention to her surroundings.
Did you need to discuss something with her?
何だよ 火憐ちゃんに何が用だったのか
Aren't you done with your Fire Sisters stuff?
前回のファイヤーシスターズ的活動
とりあえずひと段落ついたんじゃなかったっけ
うん...いえいえ
Yeah, it's really nothing...
別に何か用ってわけじゃないんだよ ただまあさ
But you know, well,
I haven't been spending much time with her lately.
なんか最近火憐ちゃんとも別行動が増えてきなーって思って
I'm sure you've already figured this out,
お兄ちゃんにはどうせバレちゃってると思うけどさあ
but I'm not as into justice as she is.
きっと私って火憐ちゃんほど情熱的に正義を信仰しているわけじゃないんだよね
I like justice... I love justice,
正義が好きて 正義が大好きだけど
but I don't really have a clear inner image of it.
だけど私の中に確固とした正義があるわけじゃないんだよ
You know how Karen-chan says
火憐ちゃんはよく言うじゃない
stuff like "My blood of justice won't forgive you"
正義の血が許さないっとか 正義の魂が燃え上がるっとか
and "My soul of justice burns"?
She does.
言うよな
But I've never felt that way before.
だけど私はそういうの感じたことがないんだ
火憐ちゃんの中には正義があるけど 私の中にはそれがない
She has it within her, but I don't.
The justice I have faith in
私の信じる私の正義は 火憐ちゃんの正義であり
is the kind Karen-chan and you have in common.
そしてお兄ちゃんの正義なんだょね
If she wasn't so sure about it,
火憐ちゃんがあそこまで正義を確信していなかったら
I wouldn't believe in something as vague as justice.
私はきっと 正義なんて不確かなもの信じていないんだよ
In that sense, you're right.
その意味では兄ちゃんの言うことは正しいよ
私の正義は偽物だよ
My justice is fake.
The reason I talk about it is because
私は正義を名乗るには 周りの意見に左右されやす過ぎるもん
I'm too easily influenced by the people around me.
If Karen-chan does what she does for other people,
他人のために正義を実行するのが火憐ちゃんなら
I do it because of their influence on me.
他人の影響で正義を実行するのが私なんだよ
We have always been different that way.
方向性には 最初からズレがあるんだ
So, Onii-chan...
だからさお兄ちゃん 最近はファイヤーシスターズも
Lately, I've been thinking it's time for the Fire Sisters to retire.
そろそろ潮時なのかなって思っちゃう場合も増えて来たんだよね
Sounds good to me.
いいんじゃねえの 別に
Actually, I think you two have gotten along a little too well.
むしろ今までが 仲良過ぎるくらいだったとそう思ってたよ
I know it isn't anything that can be helped...
別にそれが仕方がないことなのは分かってるけどさ
Once she reaches high school,
火憐ちゃんも高校生になったら
お兄ちゃんみたいに私をいじめるようになるのかなあ
will she bully me like you do?
Don't talk about me like that!
人聞きの悪いこと言ってんじゃねえよ
I consider myself a helpful and reliable older brother.
僕は頼り甲斐のあるお兄ちゃんとして
いつだってお前らの面倒を見てやっているつもりだぜ
Helpful?
面倒見るって
You mean like brushing our teeth, while touching our breasts?
歯ァ磨きながらおっぱい触るとか
よし決めた 今日火憐ちゃんが帰ってきたら
Okay, I've decided.
Once Karen-chan returns,
we'll discuss the future of the Fire Sisters!
今後のファイアーシスターズの進退について真面目に話し合おう
何だよ 場合によっては解散か
What? So you might split up?
It's possible...
ありうるね 音楽性の違いだね
We have creative differences!
If she wants to go it alone, I won't stop her.
火憐ちゃんが独立したいって言うんなら 私はそれを引き留めないよ
I shall swallow my tears and watch her go!
涙を呑んで見送るよ
解散パーティにはお兄ちゃんも参加してよね
Come to our farewell party, okay?
女子中学生とかいっぱい呼んじゃうから
I'll invite lots of middle-school girls and stuff.
Fine... I'll make the time to come.
仕方ねえな そん時くらいは時間作って顔出してやるよ
So, my helpful brother,
で 面倒見のいいお兄ちゃん
出掛けるところじゃなかったの
weren't you about to leave?
あ そうだった
Oh, that's right...
Watch the house, okay?
んじゃ 留守番よろしく
I'll be home soon.
すぐ帰ってくるつもりだけどさ
なんかついでに買いものしてくるもんあるか
Need me to pick up anything?
Nope. See you.
ないよ いってらっさい
See you...
いってらっさる
Now get back to your room.
つーかお前もお前で さっさと部屋に戻れよ
I can't open the door with you here, dressed like that.
そんなはだけた浴衣姿で廊下にいられたんじゃ 玄関が開けられねえよ
I'm telling you to stop wandering around half-dressed.
そんなあられもねえ姿で うろうろすんなっつってんだ
Don't dress like that.
みだりにみだらな恰好をするな
Hey, Tsukihi-chan...
ちょっと月火ちゃん
はい
I'm gonna take that off.
それ脱がすぞ
Wh-What?
え な...なに
Stop it, Onii-chan...
やめて お兄ちゃん 何すんの
What are you doing?
あ...あっ いやあああああ
No!
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
I knew it.
やっぱそうだ
何 何 何 何が起こってるの
What? What? What?
What's going on?
Why is my brother stripping off my clothes,
私 今 何でお兄ちゃんに脱がされて 拘束されて
grabbing my hands, and pushing me down?
挙句に押し倒されてるのかな
Um, Tsukihi-chan...
いやさ 月火ちゃん
Didn't you have a scar here?
お前この辺に 傷なかったっけ
あったはずの傷が なくなっている
The scar that should have been there is gone.
The doctors were certain that
医者から「一生消えない」と 折り紙付きで太鼓判を押されたはずなのだけれど
the scar would never, ever fade, but...
Wait. There aren't any scars on your body...
あれ あれ そういやお前
体に全然傷とか残ってねえな
そりゃ傷くらい治るよ 人間なんだから
Scars heal. I'm a human being!
Yeah, I guess so.
ん...ああ そりゃそうか
And get off of me, Onii-chan.
ていうかそろそろどいてよお兄ちゃん
傷のあるなしを確認したいだけだったら
If you wanted to see if the scar was there,
you didn't have to grab my hands and get on top of me.
手首を縛るのと馬乗りになって押し倒すのはまったく必要なかったでしょう
That's... That's true.
それは そりゃそうだ
何で今 どく前にわざわざ胸を触った
Why did you grab my breast before getting off me?
いや なんとなく
Just because.
It was right in front of me, so I wondered what it felt like.
何か目に付いたとこにあったから どんなもんかなって思って
そんな気安さで
That's the only reason?
Yeah, see...
うん ほら
Squish squish squish squish.
ぶよ ぶよ ぶよ ぶよ
足で触るな そんな楽しげな効果音など出ていない
Don't touch me with your feet!
They aren't making fun sound effects like those!
もうお兄ちゃん 妹のおっぱい触り過ぎ
Jeez, Onii-chan, you're touching your little sister's body way too much!
Um, if someone just heard that line,
それ そこだけ切り取って聞くと
なんだかものすごいキャラだな
they'd get some really strange ideas about me.
Jeez...
まったくもう まったくもう まったくもうだよまったくもう
Jeez, jeez, jeez!
何で私達姉妹 彼氏とはピュアな関係を築いているのに
Why is it that we sisters must have pure relationships with our boyfriends,
お兄ちゃんとはディープな関係を築かなくちゃいけないんだよ
but are still required to have a physical relationship with our brother?
Oh...
あ えっとなんだっけ
What was his name?
Your boyfriend.
お前の彼氏が 蝋燭沢くんだっけ
Rosokuzawa-kun?
You haven't split up yet?
まだ別れてねえの
Sorry, but I'm in love.
悪いけどラブラブっすよ
Karen-chan's boyfriend, Mizudori-kun,
火憐ちゃんのほうの瑞鳥くんは
hasn't been getting along with her that well lately.
近頃ちょっとだけ不協和音だって話も聞くけど
あっちも基本は順調なはずだよ
But I think they're all right too.
んじゃ 今度こそ行ってきます
Okay, I'm leaving now.
Don't bother coming home!
帰ってくんな お兄ちゃんの帰る家はない
There's no home for you!
いや 僕は必ず帰って来るぜ
No, I'm coming back...
お前のその胸の中にな
Inside your heart!
Flocky chou?
フロッキーシュー なんじゃこれ あれ得なくない
What is this? Is such a thing possible?
To combine the pon de ring and the French cruller...
ポン・デ・リングとフレンチクルーラーをあろうことか合体させてしまうなんて
Incredible!
ものすごく最強ではないか
オールドファッション これはもう見ただけでおいしいことが分かってしまう
Old-fashioned!
Just looking at it reveals how delicious it must be.
I can tell! I don't even have to eat it.
あーもうわかっちゃったもん 食べるまでもない いや食べるけども
I will, though!
And the mere name "tofu donut" entices me...
とうふドーナツというのも ネーミングだけでそそられてしまうのう
And look at these muffins, lined up like jewels...
ていうかここにずらーっと宝石のごとく並べられたマフィン系
何故今までこれらのマフィン系の存在を儂に隠しておったのじゃ
Why was the existence of these muffins hidden from me?
憎い奴らめ まったくもって許しがたい
Curse them! Unforgivable.
There's no need to even say this,
いやまあしかし 言うまでもないことじゃが
but the best part is having all the wonderful
ゴールデンチョコレートを始めとする
これまで食べてきた数々の選ばれしドーナツ達が
types of donuts I've consumed so far,
including the golden chocolate, laid out before me in such numbers!
こうも大量に展示されておるというところからすでに圧巻じゃ
Incredible!
パナイのう
Master, can I eat them all?
お前様よ これ全部食べてもよいのか
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
よいわけないだろ
Of course not!
え じゃあ何じゃい
Then what?
儂はこんなにも大量に陳列されとるドーナツの中から
Will I be forced to select a few for my meal
食すものを残酷に選別しなくてはならんのか
from the dozens upon dozens set out here?
I'll bring you here once a month or something.
月一くらいで連れてきたやっからよ
So you'll have to wait.
とりあえず今日はセーブしとけ
Anyway,
そうだな まずは三個くらいからスタートするのが適切なんじゃねえのか
I suppose you can pick three to start.
Oh, my master...
おいおい我があるじ様よ そうきなきなするでないぞ
Don't be so foolish.
If you're thinking about the future,
先々のことを考えれば 投資じゃと思って儂に恩を売っといたほうが
then why not consider this an investment
お前様にとってもよいのではないか
to get on my good side?
お前に恩を売ったらどうなるってんだよ
What happens if I get on your good side?
Fine... All right, all right.
あーもう 分かった分かった じゃあこうしよう
Then let's do this...
僕とお前で五個ずつ選ぼう 合計十個だ
Let's each choose five.
Ten total.
それをシェアすればいいだろう
And we can share.
その代りマフィン系とパイ系はなしだ
But no muffins and no pies.
They aren't part of the 100-yen sale.
ああいうのは今回の百円セールの対象外だからな
ん 仕方ないのう 我慢してやるか
Very well.
I accept.
So, Shinobu...
で 忍 訊きたいことがあるんだけれど
I wanted to ask you something.
今日 神原の家に行く途中と そっから帰る途中
Do you remember, on the way to Kanbaru's house and back,
those two girls who asked me for directions...
僕に道を尋ねてきた例のふたり
The older Kyoto accent one and the younger "posed look" one.
京都弁のお姉ちゃんとキメ顔のお嬢ちゃん
What did you think of them?
あいつら お前から見て どうだった
I suppose I could tell you about the "posed look" one.
あのキメ顔の小娘の方については 教えてやらんでもないの
What do you mean?
と言うと
She wasn't human.
ありゃあ人間ではない 怪異じゃ
She was a supernatural creature.
She took on a human form,
人の形は模してはおるがの
but, like me, she isn't the age she appears.
儂と同じく見た目通りの年齢ではない
And Ononoki Yotsugi is, of course, an alias.
斧乃木余接という名前も 当然のことながら偽名じゃろう
Ononoki
Yotsugi
I was wondering about her first name, Yotsugi.
下の名前 余接ってのが 僕が気になってるけどな
Kage
nui
Yo
zuru
Her first name sounds just like that Kagenui girl.
影縫のお姉さんの下の名前と対になってるってところが
Kagenui
Yozuru
はっ じゃから名前で縛っておるんじゃろうよ どうせの
She's probably using the name to bind Yotsugi!
Just like I'm bound by that brat in the Hawaiian shirt.
この儂があの軽薄な小僧の名前でがっちがちに縛られておるのと同様にの
Oshino         Meme
Animation Number 171
Oshino         Shinobu
Basically, Ononoki Yotsugi is the familiar of Kagenui Yozuru.
要するに斧乃木余接は影縫余弦の使い魔のようなもんじゃ
Familiar?
使い魔
That's what you'd call it in your culture.
この国の文化になぞらえていうなら そうじゃな
A shikigami, perhaps?
せいぜい式神といったところかの
So, of the two,
あの二人は 少なくとも影縫さんのほうは
Kagenui-san is one of those specialists...
いわゆる専門家って奴なんだ
I'm not going to share information about a respectable person.
真っ当な人間についての情報は あくまでも儂は洩らさんよ
I don't really want you to use me as a tool.
あまり便利に使われてもなんじゃしの
You won't be able to get me to talk
ドーナツをおごってもろたくらいで 儂の口は軽くなったりはせん
just by buying me donuts.
I'm not that cheap a woman.
そこまで安い女ではない
I'm not your servant or your shikigami.
儂はお前様の使い魔でもなければ式神でもないのじゃ
If you really insist on knowing,
どうしでもと言わん程度のことならば
why not ask the man sitting in the seat over there?
あそこの席に座っておるあの男にでも訊いてみたらどうじゃ
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
Kaiki-san...
貝木さん あれだけ大見得を切って
After all that grandstanding before you left,
勝ち逃げみたいな感じで去っていっといて
なんでドーナツ食ってんだよ
why are you here, eating donuts?
Some minor business.
いわゆる野暮用だよ
ただのくだらん野暮用だ
Just unpleasant minor business.
Araragi, it's nothing you need to concern yourself with.
阿良々木 お前が気にするようなことではない
いずれすぐに消えてやる
I'll be gone shortly.
I'd prefer it if you left now.
僕としては今すぐ消えて欲しいけどな
Don't be in such a hurry.
そう急かすなよ
I didn't ever want to see you again either.
お前達に二度と会いたくないのは俺の側も同じだ
お前達のせいで 俺は大損こいたんだからな
Because of you, I lost a lot of money.
You do know Kagenui Yozuru and Ononoki Yotsugi, right?
影縫余弦と斧乃木余接 知ってるよな
知りたいか 教えてやる 金を払え
You want to know about them?
I'll tell you. Pay up first.
Fine...
ああ わかったよ
How much do I need to pay for you to tell me?
で いくら払えばいいんだよその二人の情報にはよ
どれ
Let me see.
That will do.
まあいいだろう
Araragi.
阿良々木 お前と戦場ヶ原若い男女の前途を祝する意味で
I'll allow you to pay with this meager change,
as a gift to honor your relationship with Senjougahara.
この程度のはした金で許しておいてやろう
Tell me about...
教えろよ 影縫余弦と斧乃木余接だ
Kagenui Yozuru and Ononoki Yotsugi!
They are specialists...
あいつらは専門家だよ
俺と同じ ゴーストバスターだ
Ghost busters like me.
Of course, whereas I'm a fake, they're real.
もっとも 俺が偽物であるのに対して あいつらは本物だ
I'm a con man, but they are exorcists.
俺が詐欺師なら あいつらは陰陽師だ
Exorcists?
陰陽師
Naturally, I said "they."
勢いで『ら』などと言ってしまったが
厳密には陰陽師は影縫のほうで
But to be precise, Kagenui is the exorcist,
and Ononoki is her shikigami.
斧乃木はあくまで式神だそうだがな
You know them?
知り合いなのか
Why would you think so?
なぜそう思う
Well, from the way you talked.
いや 言い方が  その なんとなく
Just the way you spoke implied it.
口ぶりがそんな風かなって思って
I merely know their names.
名を知っているだけだ
影縫のほうが 業界ではそこそこの有名人だからな
Kagenui is rather famous in the business.
Kagenui Yozuru and Ononoki Yotsugi
影縫余弦と斧乃木余接
are modern-day exorcists.
あくなき現代の陰陽師
Hey, Araragi,
なあ 阿良々木よ
専門家とはいえ 連中の専門は非常に狭い
they're specialists, but they
specialize in a very limited field.
That two-person cell specializes
あのツーマンセルの専門は
in immortal creatures.
不死身の怪異なんだぜ
An exorcist specializing in immortal monsters?
不死身の怪異を専門にする陰陽師か
やれやれ 標的は僕とお前ってことになるんだろうなあ やっぱり
Jeez...
Then they're probably after you and me.
ふふん わしとお前様が標的のう
You think we're their targets?
しかし そうとは限らんぞ 我が主様
But perhaps we are not, my master.
不死身の怪異など わしは死ぬほど食うて来た
I've eaten many immortal creatures.
わしもわしで 立派な不死身殺しじゃよ
I kill the immortal too.
C
Timed Light
大体 そんなことを言い出したら
Those supernatural beings aren't really immortal.
They aren't even alive.
不死身も何も 怪異はそもそも生きておらんじゃろうに
Yeah...
ああ まあ 生きてねえもんに不死身も何もねえよな
Well, I guess if you're not living, you can't die.
So I guess anything supernatural is immortal.
だったら 怪異は全部 不死身みてえなもんなのか
でも そういう定議論はともかくとしてさ
But strict definitions aside,
when you say that they might not be after us, Shinobu,
僕達が標的とは限らないっていうんだったら
忍 お前はこの町に僕達以外に吸血鬼がいるかもしれないって言いたいのか
does that mean there are other vampires in this city besides us?
吸血鬼とは限らんがの いても不思議はあるまい
They don't have to be vampires.
It wouldn't be strange.
否 不思議はある
No.
I suppose it would.
Come to think of it,
言われてみりゃあ 僕の周囲だけに限って観察してみても
even just among those I know,
怪異を体内に宿しながら生きてる人間ってのは何人かいるんだよな
many people have supernatural creatures inside them.
たとえば左手に猿を宿した神原駿河がそうだし
Like Kanbaru Suruga with a monkey in her left hand.
ABERRATION
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
Or Hanekawa Tsubasa with a cat inside her mind.
たとえば精神に猫を宿した羽川翼がそうだ
So it wouldn't be particularly odd if there were others
だったら 他にも体内に怪異を宿した僕の知らない人間がいても
housing creatures that I don't know about.
不自然じゃない
Kagenui-san and Ononoki-chan.
影縫さんと斧乃木ちゃん
あの排ビルを根城にするあたりが
They're likely in the same business as Oshino
since they're setting up base in the same place.
Homeless           Middle-Aged
忍野の同業者って感じか
I should deal with them quickly.
早目早目に対処しといたほうがいいかもな
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
あ おどれ
You...
Hi.
どうも
First, I should thank you.
まず礼を言うとかなあかんねや
おどれの言う通りに進んだら
I followed the directions you gave me,
and it led me to the Eikou Cram School.
叡考塾にはちゃんと着けたわ
その上 ほんまに余弦にも教えてくれたそうやん
And you helped Yotsugi as well.
その すみません
Um, I'm sorry...
I'd like to clear something up.
はっきりさせておきたいことがあるんですけれど
あなた達二人は 僕とこいつを退治するためにこの町に来たんですよね
You came to this city to exterminate us, right?
この世にあるまじき不死者とその眷属として
You've come to kill her, an immortal creature not of this world,
along with me, her servant, yes?
僕達を殺しに来たんですよね
二人続けて道を訊いてきたのも 偶然なんかじゃなくて
Both of you asking me for
directions was no coincidence.
You were investigating me.
あれは様子見みたいなものだった
鬼畜な兄やん なんや知らん
Devil boy,
you seem to be operating under a misconception.
おどれ 勘違いしとるみたいやな
Matters pertaining to the iron-blooded, cold-blooded, and hot-blooded
鉄血にして熱血にして冷血の吸血鬼
killer of monsters and lord of the night,
怪異殺しの怪異の王
キスショット・アセロラオリオン・ハートアンダーブレード
Kiss-shot Acerola-orion Heart-under-blade,
に関する諸問題は既に解決したことになっとる
have already been resolved.
And our industry hardly has the free time
ちょっと後遺症が残っとる程度の普通の人間に対してリソースを割けるほど
to squander resources on a normal human
うち共の業界も閑古鳥が鳴いてえへんわ
with a few lingering aftereffects.
Of course, that's thanks to Oshino-kun's habitual interference and meddling.
それはでも 言うたら忍野君の世話焼き
お得意十八番のお節介のお陰っちゅうことになるんやろけどな
Oshino-kun?
忍野君
いや 今 忍野君と言ったか
Did she just say Oshino-kun?
Yellow Scene
Animation Number "None"
Hey, master.
おい お前様よ  余計なことを思考するでない
Now's not the time to get distracted.
You have other things to worry about at the moment.
今お前様には他に考えねばならんことがあるじゃろうが
That's right. That's right...
そうだ そうだよ
If they aren't here for us,
Oshino Shinobu and Araragi Koyomi,
もしも阿良々木暦や忍野忍を目当てとして来たのでないと言うのなら
どうして影縫さんと斧乃木ちゃんはここにいる
then why have Kagenui-san and Ononoki-chan come here?
Shut up! Shut up, shut up, shut up!
ああもううるさいし うるさいしうるさいしうるさいし
一体いつまでインターホン鳴らしてるのよ
How long will you stand there, pressing the doorbell?
居留守を使ってるのがわっかんないの！?
Can't you tell I'm pretending not to be here?
Unlimited Rulebook.
『例外のほうが多い規則（ｱﾝﾘﾐﾃｯﾄﾞ・ﾙｰﾙﾌﾞｯｸ）』
僕はキメ顔でそう言った
I said with a posed look.
落ち着きいや 鬼畜な兄やん
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
Calm down, devil boy.
Don't get so worked up.
そうかっかすんなや
Oshino-kun would probably say something like,
こういうとき 忍野君ならこない言うんかな
元気ええなあ なんぞええことでもあったんけ
"You're looking lively. Did something good happen?"
ざっけんな てめえ てめえら
Shut up!
You...
You bastards...
妹を 僕の妹を 月火ちゃんを 許さねえ
You killed my sister...
My sister Tsukihi-chan...
I'll make you pay!
んん なんや あの子 おどれの妹か
What, that was your sister?
I see.
ああそうか そういやおどれも阿良々木やったな
Right, your name is Araragi too.
ただの同姓やと思っとったけど
I thought it was just a coincidence.
I understand.
そうかいな 情報にノイズがあったっちゅうことか
Our information had some gaps.
やとしたら おどれにとってはショッキングな映像やったな
Then that must have been quite a shock for you.
すまん すまん
Sorry, sorry.
You think an apology will help?
謝ってすむかあ てめえ
見てみいや
Observe.
あ あれ
Devil boy,
鬼のお兄ちゃん あなたはよくよく不死身の怪異に縁があるようだね
you appear to have a thing for immortal creatures.
あなたの妹は不死身の怪鳥に犯されている
Your sister is possessed by an immortal bird.
あれは端っからあなたの妹ではなく
That was never truly your sister.
It is human, yet not human.
人間であって人間でない
What you see there is the rare firebird,
あそこのあれは世にも珍しい火の鳥
the evil phoenix.
邪悪なるフェニックスだよ
僕はキメ顔でそう言った
I said with a posed look.
Enough.
やめい うぬら それ以上の狼藉は許さね
I will not allow any more of this.
You can't wish
うぬらとて ここでこれ以上の騒ぎを起こすことを望んでおるわけではなかろうよ
to attract more attention than you already have, correct?
んーん うちは別にかめへんけど
We don't care.
We're not so clever as to worry ourselves about time or place...
時と場合を考慮するほど うちはお利口さんやないからな
And how will you stop us?
ちゅうか 許さんゆうて
今のおどれに何ができるっちゅうねん
What can you do?
吸血鬼 元吸血鬼
Vampire...
Former vampire.
スキルをなくしたおどれなんぞ
Without your skills, you're no threat to me.
うちにとってはまるで脅威やないで
Possibly!
かもしれんな
But regardless of whether that's true for you, is it true for the girl?
しかし うぬはそうでも そちらの小娘はどうかな
わしのエナジードレインに耐え切れるほど強力な怪異とはとても思えぬが
I doubt she's strong enough
to withstand my energy drain.
そしてそやつを吸い切れば
And if I drain her dry,
うぬとも十分 わしは渡り合えるのではないかのう
I think I could handle you afterward...
A bluff!
ハッタリだ
I'm not going to interfere with you.
わしは何も うぬらの邪魔をしようというわけではない
ただ 一旦退けと言っておるだけじゃ
But I shall request that you withdraw for now.
You could do that for me, couldn't you?
その程度の頼みなら きいてくれてもよいのではないか
Time isn't an important factor for you.
うぬらにとっては 時間は重要な問題ではあるまい
ふん まあええやろ
Fine, then.
お言葉の通り  一旦退くわ
As you say, we'll leave now.
Let's go.
退かしてもらいましょ
Despite what I said,
in the present situation, we have no interest
時と場合に無頓着ゆうても さすがのうちも
まさか兄の前で妹を退治する気はあれへんかったからな
in killing a little sister in front of her brother's eyes.
Of course...
ゆうても
ほんまの妹やないんやけど
she isn't your real sister.
Not my real sister...
本物の妹じゃない 偽物の妹
A fake sister?
I'm sure the devil boy
鬼畜なお兄やんにも 身辺の整理をする時間は必要やろ
needs time to get this straight in his head.
We'll give you time out of respect for the legendary vampire.
伝説の吸血鬼に敬意を表して その時間を与えたるわ
We'll pretend to fall for your bluff,
その天晴れなハッタリに黙されといたるさかい
so prepare yourselves however you like.
心の準備でも身体の支度でもなんでもせえや
We'll return tomorrow.
明日 また来るわ それまでに色々整理しとき
Be sure everything has been handled by then.
Running won't help.
逃げても無駄やで
To be clear, neither of us is as easy to deal with as Oshino-kun.
言っとくけどうちらは 忍野君ほど甘くはない
狙った獲物は逃さへんのや
We won't let any prey escape.
And if you try to stop us,
邪魔立てしよう言うんなら 無害認定なんざシカト決めて
we'll ignore the ruling deciding you were harmless
and we'll eliminate you too.
おどれらごと始末したるわ ほな
Goodbye.
Why...
なんで
なんで月火ちゃんを狙うんだ
Why are you after Tsukihi-chan?
月火ちゃんにはあなた達から狙われる理由なんか
There's no reason for you to...
There is.
あるやん ありゃあ怪異やで バケモンや
She's a supernatural creature...
化物の偽物が人間の家族に混じって人間の振りして
A monstrous fake that snuck into a human family,
pretended to be human,
人間を騙して生きとんやで
and deceived humans!
そういうのを指してな
We call that evil.
うちらは『悪』ゆうねん
We're the good guys...
うちら正義の味方としちゃあ 見過せんよ
So we cannot ignore a con like that.
そないな詐欺はな
We can't allow it.
許せんよ
Dialogue Script - Nisio Isin
4-Koma Illustrations - Haritama Hiroki
Preview
It's me, Araragi Koyomi.
We're the fire-...!
Silent
You may be disgruntled to be told this,
but don't you think there have been rather too many sequels, prequels, part two's, second seasons,
I saw it on TV!
I want in on the action!
Say that earlier!
reinventions, additional content works, spin-offs, side stories, bonus material works, and revivals as of late?
What the hell is
going on here, fire sisters?
Whoa! Onii-chan!
I mean, I'm a fan myself, so I can't help being happy,
You two
are still fakes!
I'll think about it
Huh? Is that the script?
Slipping Out
but if this keeps up nothing really new will be made,
and before long we will bitterly complain about the deplorable decline of modern literature.
A Technicolor Animated Movie
in All Theaters
Kizumonogatari
Production Underway
Starring Araragi Koyomi
That's what I told Sengoku the other day, and this is how she answered:
Don't worry, Koyomi Onii-chan.
Our hearts are one!
We're the fire sisters!
This is nothing new.
It's been like that since the dawn of time.
Next time. Tsukihi Phoenix, Part 4.
Next Time
Tsukihi Phoenix Part 4
Naturally, that will be the last one.
You'll see us again soon!